### Hezron Kimutai Chelimo

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hezron-kimutai-603b62173/ | +25083375100 | hezronchelimo.hc@gmail.com | https://github.com/hezronkimutai

### **Software Engineer**

A strong conceptual thinker who has a keen interest in all things related to the software world. I have the ability and experience needed to design and execute complex software projects for a diverse variety of users. I am committed to having an impact on the future of any company that I work for, and possess the enthusiasm and commitment to learn and develop my career within a fast paced and growing business.

## **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

Javascript(NodeJS, React), HTML5/CSS3/SASS, Python3(Flask/Django), CI/CD, Version Control, Caching, Docker, SQL, and NoSQL Databases, TDD, Agile development, Digital Ocean, and little of AWS, GCP, and Azure.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Software Engineer** (june 2020 - present) **PickMeUp** 

- Worked as a UI/UX. I built user friendly user interfaces for the PickMeUp company. I built a nice admin dashboard with analytics charts and with google maps API integrated.
- Worked as Backend developer. I built a backend application using typescript. I used the microservice architecture and RabbitMq as a messaging broker.

Software Engineer (February 2020 - may 2020) Datasystem limited, Nairobi, Kenya

Worked as a Full Stack Engineer (NodeJS/NestJs/React).

I was part of the team that initiated the creation of one of Data systems LTD e-commerce products.

Software Engineer(June 2019 - april 2020) Andela, Kigali, Rwanda

Drive the development process of some of the internal tools for Andela and work with its external partners. Worked with, Nodejs, ReactJs and Typescript

**Software Engineer** (November 2018 - present)

**Fiver** 

Works as a Freelancer. I build web applications for my clients using Python/Flask/Django, Node/Express Js/NestJs and React.

## **Other Contributions**

- **1. Contributor Custom React Pages.** I am one of the top contributors to custom react pages. An npm package for react applications that make pagination easy. (Npm Link, Github Link)
- **2. nodejs-api-cli**. A scaffolding tool for making it easier to speed the development process/setting for NodeJs API application for different frameworks. (<u>Github link</u>)

## **PROJECTS**

- <a href="https://evenhelp.io">https://evenhelp.io</a>
- https://havascore.netlify.app/

# **EDUCATION**

**BSc. Electrical & Electronics Engineering,** Machakos University(2014-2017)